Guide to the Edgar Parin and Ingri D'Aulaire Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- I. February 2006 Acquisition, 1931-1976; 38.13 linear ft. (96 boxes) + 7 broadsides, 37 rolls
  - Material Housed in Custom Manuscript Boxes
    - Wings for Per
      - Original hand-colored lithographs and title design, circa 1944 (Box 45)
  - Oversize Material
    - Abraham Lincoln
      - Two sets of proofs, circa 1939 (Box 46 (Oversize))
      - Proofs, color and black and white, circa 1939 (Box 46 (Oversize))
      - Bound scrapbook titled, "Abraham Lincoln," includes letters and pictures by school children and cover letter from teacher, circa 1939 (Box 46 (Oversize))
      - Pencil drawings, circa 1939 (Box 46 (Oversize))
      - Color proof of dust jacket on board, circa 1939 (Box 46 (Oversize))
      - Black and white proofs, matted, circa 1939; 4 (Box 46 (Oversize))
      - Color proofs, matted, circa 1939 (Box 46 (Oversize))
      - Poster, circa 1939 (Box 46 (Oversize))
      - Proofs, circa 1939 (Box 46 (Oversize))
    - Animals Everywhere
      - Proofs in varying states, with 2 overlays of title page, hand-colored, circa 1940 (Box 46 (Oversize))
      - Color proofs, circa 1940; 5 folders (Box 47 (Oversize))
      - Blue and white and black and white proofs, circa 1940 (Box 47 (Oversize))
      - Black and white proofs, circa 1940 (Box 47 (Oversize))
    - Benjamin Franklin
      - Hand-colored proofs, circa 1950 (Box 47 (Oversize))
      - Proofs, matted, circa 1950; 4 folders (Box 47 (Oversize))
      - Proofs in various stages, circa 1950 (Box 47 (Oversize))
      - Proofs for color sketches; black and white proofs; color progressive proofs for dust jacket; color proofs, circa 1950 (Box 47 (Oversize))
    - Buffalo Bill
      - Proofs, circa 1952; 3 folders (Box 48 (Oversize))
      - Matted proofs, circa 1952; 10 (Box 48 (Oversize))
      - Matted proofs, circa 1952; 19 (Box 49 (Oversize))
      - Matted proofs, circa 1952; 14 (Box 50 (Oversize))
      - Sketches, circa 1952 (Box 51 (Oversize))
    - Children of the Northlights
      - Hand-colored illustrations, studies, and sketches, circa 1935 (Box 51 (Oversize))
      - Color and black and white proofs; duplicates titled "Lapp Children"; proof titled in Edgar's hand; proof for second edition dust jacket, circa 1963 (Box 51 (Oversize))
      - Typescript draft, bound, undated (Box 51 (Oversize))
    - Columbus
      - Acetate drawings in black and white, some mounted, circa 1955; 8 folders (Box 52 (Oversize))
      - Acetate drawings in black and white, some mounted, circa 1955; 7 (Box 53 (Oversize))
      - Matted color proofs, circa 1955; 7 folders (Box 53 (Oversize))
      - Matted color proofs, circa 1955; 12 (Box 54 (Oversize))
      - Color print, circa 1955 (Box 54 (Oversize))
    - The Conquest of the Atlantic
      - Unbound publisher's proof and dust jacket, circa 1933 (Box 55 (Oversize))
      - Proofs, color and black and white some titled by hand, circa 1933; 2 (Box 55 (Oversize))
      - Signed proofs, color and black and white, circa 1933 (Box 55 (Oversize))
      - Matted black and white proofs, circa 1933 (Box 55 (Oversize))
      - Sketch books with a faint drawing of girl on cover includes manuscript notes and pencil drawing, circa 1933 (Box 55 (Oversize))
    - Don't Count Your Chicks
      - Miscellaneous set of proofs, color and black and white, circa 1943; 2 (Box 55 (Oversize))
      - Complete set of proofs, circa 1943; 2 folders (Box 55 (Oversize))
      - Matted proofs, circa 1943; 2 folders (Box 55 (Oversize))
      - Paperback edition, circa 1943 (Box 56 (Oversize))
      - Color proofs, circa 1943 (Box 56 (Oversize))
      - Matted proofs, circa 1943; 24 (Box 56 (Oversize))
      - Matted proofs, circa 1943; 5 folders (Box 57 (Oversize))
    - East of the Sun and West of the Moon
      - Matted proofs; end papers; acetates with drawings; film; proofs for dust jacket, circa 1938; 10 (Box 58 (Oversize))
      - Matted proofs; end papers; acetates with drawings; film; proofs for dust jacket, circa 1938; 12 folders (Box 59 (Oversize))
      - Dust jacket, 3 states of proofs; misc. proofs; pages cut from book inserted in a proof for dust jacket, circa 1938; 3 folders (Box 60 (Oversize))
      - Matted proofs, circa 1938; 2 folders (Box 60 (Oversize))
    - Foxie
      - Films and original acetate drawings laid into green end paper for Norse Gods and Giants, circa 1949 (Box 60 (Oversize))
      - Proofs; guide for dust jacket; photostats, circa 1949; 2 (Box 60 (Oversize))
      - Editorial library copy; photocopies with sheets pasted in, circa 1949 (Box 60 (Oversize))
    - George Washington
      - Matted color proofs, circa 1936; 9 folders (Box 61 (Oversize))
      - Matted color proofs, circa 1936 (Box 61 (Oversize))
      - Color proofs, circa 1936 (Box 61 (Oversize))
    - Ingri and Edgar Parin D'Aulaire's Book of Greek Myths
      - Blue line paste-up and illustrations with some photostats, circa 1962; 3 (Box 62 (Oversize))
      - Europa and Cadmus: 1 original pen and ink hand-colored drawing, mounted with typewritten page of text; 6 proofs in various states; original drawings on acetates, black and white proof, circa 1962; 3 (Box 62 (Oversize))
      - Europa and Cadmus: 1 original pen and ink hand-colored drawing, mounted with typewritten page of text; 6 proofs in various states; original drawings on acetates, black and white proof, circa 1962; 10 (Box 63 (Oversize))
      - Pencil, pen and ink, and hand-colored illustrations, circa 1962 (Box 64 (Oversize))
      - Sketches and original drawings, circa 1962 (Box 64 (Oversize))
      - Miscellaneous proofs, circa 1962; 4 folders (Box 65 (Oversize))
      - Early state of publisher's proof in 5 groups of uncut sheets, circa 1962 (Box 65 (Oversize))
      - Proofs in blue for text and editor's proof in black and white for the text with corrections, circa 1962; 5 folders (Box 66 (Oversize))
    - Leif the Lucky
      - Matted proofs, circa 1941; 9 folders (Box 67 (Oversize))
      - Proofs and reviews, circa 1941 (Box 68 (Oversize))
      - Miscellaneous pages, proofs, etc., circa 1941; 8 folders (Box 68 (Oversize))
      - Miscellaneous pages, proofs, etc., circa 1941; 7 folders (Box 69 (Oversize))
      - Publisher's catalog, typed reviews, circa 1941 (Box 69 (Oversize))
      - Various proofs, circa 1941; 2 folders (Box 69 (Oversize))
      - Proofs, some hand-signed, circa 1941 (Box 69 (Oversize))
      - Black and white and color drawings; octagonal shaped card with hand-colored boarder and black and white center; publishers' catalogue, circa 1941 (Box 69 (Oversize))
      - Miscellaneous proofs, circa 1941; 2 folders (Box 70 (Oversize))
    - The Lord's Prayer
      - Original drawing, circa 1934 (Box 70 (Oversize))
      - Set of proofs in varying states, circa 1934 (Box 70 (Oversize))
    - The Magic Meadow
      - Acetates, circa 1958; 2 folders (Box 70 (Oversize))
      - Acetates, circa 1958; 8 folders (Box 71 (Oversize))
      - Acetates, circa 1958; 7 folders (Box 72 (Oversize))
      - Acetates, circa 1958; 3 folders (Box 73 (Oversize))
    - The Magic Rug
      - "Elementary English"; pamphlet, 1953 April (Box 73 (Oversize))
        Includes article about Edgar Parin and Ingri D'Aulaire.
      - Historical, hand-colored illustration studies and 3 pencil drawings, circa 1931 (Box 73 (Oversize))
      - 2 color proofs imprinted WCD Glaser; 4 small color proofs, circa 1931 (Box 73 (Oversize))
      - Proofs in various states of dust jacket, circa 1931; 2 (Box 73 (Oversize))
    - Nils
      - Title page proofs, circa 1948 (Box 74 (Oversize))
      - Original hand-colored title page; hand-colored and pencil illustrations, circa 1948 (Box 74 (Oversize))
      - Matted color proofs, circa 1948; 10 (Box 74 (Oversize))
      - Color proof, circa 1948 (Box 74 (Oversize))
      - Proofs in various states, circa 1948; 3 folders (Box 75 (Oversize))
      - Matted proofs, circa 1948; 6 folders (Box 75 (Oversize))
      - Matted color proofs, circa 1948; 3 folders (Box 76 (Oversize))
      - Proofs, circa 1948; 2 folders (Box 76 (Oversize))
      - Pencil drawings, circa 1948 (Box 76 (Oversize))
    - Norse Gods and Giants
      - Photocopy of layout with correction notes by editor and D'Aulaire, circa 1967 (Box 77 (Oversize))
      - Set of trial sheets to test color of ink, circa 1967 (Box 77 (Oversize))
      - Color separations for contents page, circa 1967 (Box 77 (Oversize))
      - Color separations for p. 74-75, circa 1967; 4 folders (Box 77 (Oversize))
      - Ther-a-grays of color separations for first image, circa 1967; 3 (Box 77 (Oversize))
      - International Wildlife magazine, original acetate drawing on p. 48, 1979 October; 2 (Box 77 (Oversize))
      - Paste-up in blue, circa 1967; 2 folders (Box 77 (Oversize))
      - Original drawings on acetate, circa 1967; 3 folders (Box 78 (Oversize))
      - Original drawings on acetate, circa 1967; 11 (Box 79 (Oversize))
      - Original drawings on acetate, circa 1967; 16 (Box 80 (Oversize))
    - Ola
      - Pictorial front cover board, mounted, circa 1932 (Box 81 (Oversize))
      - Miscellaneous color proofs, circa 1932 (Box 81 (Oversize))
      - Pictorial board for cover, circa 1932 (Box 81 (Oversize))
      - Hand-colored proofs, circa 1932 (Box 81 (Oversize))
      - Color and black and white proofs, circa 1932 (Box 81 (Oversize))
      - Matted color proofs, circa 1932; 2 folders (Box 81 (Oversize))
      - Matted proofs, "hand-pulled", circa 1932 (Box 81 (Oversize))
      - Miscellaneous proofs, circa 1932; 2 folders (Box 81 (Oversize))
      - Sheet of cut-out dolls, circa 1932 (Box 82 (Oversize))
      - 2 maps; 1 hand-colored illustration; 7 pencil studies, circa 1932 (Box 82 (Oversize))
      - Miscellaneous, circa 1932 (Box 82 (Oversize))
    - Ola and Blakken and Line, Sine, Trine
      - Set of proofs in color with black and white proofs, including proof of title; set of later color proofs, circa 1933 (Box 82 (Oversize))
      - Fold-out of promotional book stand for Ola and Ola and Blakken and Line, Sine, Trine, circa 1933 (Box 83 (Oversize))
      - Miscellaneous proof in variant states; matted color proofs; "hand-pulled" proofs, circa 1933; 9 (Box 83 (Oversize))
    - The Star-Spangled Banner
      - Unbound publisher's proof in 3 gatherings, circa 1942 (Box 84 (Oversize))
      - Color and black and white proofs, circa 1942; 16 (Box 84 (Oversize))
      - Proofs, circa 1942 (Box 85 (Oversize))
      - Research papers, circa 1942; 3 folders (Box 85 (Oversize))
    - The Terrible Troll-Bird
      - Progressive proofs, circa 1976; 2 folders (Box 86 (Oversize))
      - Mock-up with pasted text and illustrations in proof; set of film drawing; set of photostats; 8 acetate drawings, circa 1976; 5 folders (Box 86 (Oversize))
      - Hand-colored illustrations; signed limited print, circa 1976 (Box 86 (Oversize))
      - Overlays with original art including front cover of dust jacket, circa 1976 (Box 86 (Oversize))
    - Too Big
      - Matted color and black and white proofs, circa 1945; 8 (Box 87 (Oversize))
      - Matted color and black and white proofs, circa 1945; 16 folders (Box 88 (Oversize))
      - Matted color and black and white proofs, circa 1945; 4 (Box 89 (Oversize))
    - D'Aulaires' Trolls
      - Proofs, circa 1972; 3 folders (Box 90 (Oversize))
      - Press sheets, circa 1972 (Box 90 (Oversize))
      - Blue line paste sheets, circa 1972 (Box 90 (Oversize))
      - Color proofs, circa 1972 (Box 90 (Oversize))
      - Reproduction sheets labeled in Edgar's hand, circa 1972 (Box 90 (Oversize))
      - Title set-up, circa 1972 (Box 90 (Oversize))
      - Drawings, circa 1972 (Box 90 (Oversize))
      - Handwritten sheets re. print counts, circa 1972 (Box 90 (Oversize))
      - Troll-theme Christmas card, 1972 (Box 91 (Oversize))
      - Preliminary sketches, circa 1972; 2 folders (Box 91 (Oversize))
      - Signed cropped proof, circa 1972 (Box 91 (Oversize))
      - Mounted color proofs, circa 1972 (Box 91 (Oversize))
      - Sketches, circa 1972 (Box 91 (Oversize))
      - Acetates, circa 1972; 3 folders (Box 91 (Oversize))
      - Jacket cover, circa 1972 (Box 91 (Oversize))
      - Lithograph on glossy paper, circa 1972 (Box 91 (Oversize))
    - The Two Cars
      - Matted acetates, circa 1955 (Box 92 (Oversize))
      - Acetates, circa 1955 (Box 92 (Oversize))
      - Acetates, circa 1955; 7 folders (Box 93 (Oversize))
    - Wings for Per
      - Matted proofs, circa 1944; 12 (Box 94 (Oversize))
      - Matted proofs, circa 1944; 15 (Box 95 (Oversize))
  - Objects
    - Buffalo Bill, Medal from Boy's Club of America (Box 96 (Oversize))
    - East of the Sun and West of the Moon, copper plates and related papers, 5 (Box 96 (Oversize))
  - Audiovisual Material
    - Columbus, record album, 3 (Box 234 (Record album storage))
  - Rolled Items
    - Abraham Lincoln (Box 97 (Roll))
    - Abraham Lincoln (Box 98 (Roll))
    - Abraham Lincoln (Box 99 (Roll))
    - Animals Everywhere (Box 100 (Roll))
    - Ben Franklin (Box 101 (Roll))
    - Columbus (Box 102 (Roll))
    - Columbus (Box 103 (Roll))
    - Columbus (Box 104 (Roll))
    - The Conquest of the Atlantic (Box 105 (Roll))
    - Foxie (Box 106 (Roll))
    - Foxie (Box 107 (Roll))
    - Ingri and Edgar Parin D'Aulaire's Book of Greek Myths (Box 108 (Roll))
    - Ingri and Edgar Parin D'Aulaire's Book of Greek Myths (Box 109 (Roll))
    - Ingri and Edgar Parin D'Aulaire's Book of Greek Myths (Box 110 (Roll))
    - Ingri and Edgar Parin D'Aulaire's Book of Greek Myths (Box 111 (Roll))
    - Ingri and Edgar Parin D'Aulaire's Book of Greek Myths (Box 112 (Roll))
    - Leif the Lucky (Box 113 (Roll))
    - Leif the Lucky (Box 114 (Roll))
    - The Lord's Prayer (Box 115 (Roll))
    - The Lord's Prayer (Box 116 (Roll))
    - Norse Gods and Giants (Box 117 (Roll))
    - Norse Gods and Giants (Box 118 (Roll))
    - Norse Gods and Giants (Box 119 (Roll))
    - Ola and Blakken and Line, Sine, Trine (Box 120 (Roll))
    - The Star-Spangled Banner (Box 121 (Roll))
    - The Terrible Troll-Bird (Box 122 (Roll))
    - The Terrible Troll-Bird (Box 123 (Roll))
    - The Terrible Troll-Bird (Box 124 (Roll))
    - The Terrible Troll-Bird (Box 125 (Roll))
    - The Terrible Troll-Bird (Box 126 (Roll))
    - The Terrible Troll-Bird (Box 127 (Roll))
    - The Terrible Troll-Bird (Box 128 (Roll))
    - The Terrible Troll-Bird (Box 129 (Roll))
    - D'Aulaires' Trolls (Box 130 (Roll))
    - D'Aulaires' Trolls (Box 131 (Roll))
    - D'Aulaires' Trolls (Box 132 (Roll))
    - Empty roll (Box 133 (Roll))
  - Broadside Folders
    - Abraham Lincoln (Box 134 (Broadside))
    - Foxie, dust jacket with an incomplete unbound proof lacking jacket (Box 135 (Broadside))
    - Leif the Lucky, proofs (Box 136 (Broadside))
    - The Magic Rug, large group of proofs, dust jacket, color proof of end paper (Box 137 (Broadside))
    - Norse Gods and Giants, charcoal drawing; color drawings; acetate; sketches; hand-colored illustration of end paper with preliminary sketch; hand-colored illustrations for front and rear of dust jacket; pencil and paste-up cover for dust jacket (Box 138 (Broadside))
    - The Terrible Troll-Bird, set of film from lithographs on plastic (Box 139 (Broadside))
    - The Terrible Troll-Bird, dust jackets and poster (Box 140 (Broadside))
- II. March 2006 Acquisition, 1930-1978; 14.8 linear ft. (40 boxes) + 16 film reels, 1 broadside folder, 1 roll
  Organized into six groupings: Unpublished Works, German and English Language Books, Other Papers, Objects, Audiovisual Material, and Oversize.
  This portion of the collection contains material documenting the professional and personal life of the D'Aulaires. The acquisition largely includes material surrounding the D'Aulaires' publications -- such as correspondence and reviews -- rather than extensive materials from the production of their books. There are some documents, such as drafts and proofs, relating to unpublished works and works published in German and in English. Material relating to the D'Aulaire's artwork can be found in sketches, drawings, and various objects relating to the artistic process, such as painter's palettes and other art supplies. Other Papers also includes correspondence and photographs relating to the D'Aulaires' personal life and Objects includes personal effects (such as eyeglasses). Audiovisual Material, largely home movies and a documentary film about the D'Aulaires ( Children of the Northlights ), similarly provides insight into the D'Aulaires' lives and careers.
  Former call number: Uncat MSS 858.
  Donated by Nils Daulaire and Per Ola D'Aulaire, 2006.
  Similar material can also be found in I. February 2006 Acquisition, III. March 2006 Acquisition, and IV. September 2007 Acquisition.
  Boxes 172-189 (films and reel-to-reel sound recordings): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Box 190 (videocassette and DVD): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Unpublished Works
    - "Acts of Apostles," autograph manuscript, notebook, notes, sketches and historical background, 2 (Box 141)
    - "The Boy Who Was So Lonesome," autograph manuscript and typescript (Box 141)
    - "He Himself Goes Abroad," sketches with text, notes, outline, sketchbook (Box 141)
    - "It Can't Happen Here," typescript with a number of pages in Norwegian (Box 141)
    - "Kari," corrected typescript, translation by Ingri's sister, Pet Bugge; typescript in Norwegian, drawings, sketches, proof for dust jacket (Box 141)
    - "The Mermaid and the Fisherman," notebooks and folders containing manuscript material, 4 (Box 141)
    - "The Mermaid and the Fisherman," notebooks and folders containing manuscript material, 4 folders (Box 142)
    - "The Noisy Boy," autograph manuscript, pen and ink and pencil drawings (Box 142)
    - "Princeton Goes to Harvard," drawing, typescript and manuscript pages (Box 142)
  - German and English Language Books
    - Annrud. "Sidsel Longskirt and Solve Suntrap." Includes for "Sidsel Longskirt": a large group of proofs, 2 (Box 142)
    - Arnold. "Der Goldene Brunen," two original watercolors, proofs, publisher's advertisement (Box 142)
    - Seabrook. "Gao of the Ivory Coast," original pencil drawings and proofs (Box 142)
  - Other Papers
    - Overprinted color prints for various books (Box 142)
    - Pencil drawings of life in Hell (Box 142)
    - Original watercolor for a book fair (Box 142)
    - Christmas card in envelope, 1972 (Box 142)
    - Proof of illustration of 4 children reading books with animals around them (Box 142)
    - Original pencil drawing with initials "BA" (possibly Boris Artzybasheff) (Box 142)
    - Sketches, 2 (Box 142)
    - Sketches, 2 (Box 143)
    - Envelopes and folders titled in Edgar's hand, 2 (Box 143)
    - "The Cat Who Wasn't a Cat," sketch book with illustrated front cover. Contains original pencil drawings, manuscript text, guide sheet; miniature book with text and pencil drawing; handwritten manuscript pages with corrections, drawings, typescript (Box 144)
    - "Mura and Gedichte," manuscript of Edgar Parin's first book written when he was living in Munich, 13-14 years old with bookplate "Ex Libris Parin," pen and ink and color drawings (Box 145)
    - "Story of Life on the Lofoten Islands in Norway," drawings, preliminary sketches, some typewritten text, pages with manuscript corrections, annotated drawings, notes, clippings, related papers (Box 146)
    - Professional Papers
      - Correspondence, 1930s-1970; 9 folders (Box 147)
      - Fan mail, [1952-1983]; 7 folders (Box 148)
      - Ingri and Edgar Parin D'Aulaire's Book of Greek Myths - correspondence (Box 148)
      - Radio and television correspondence (Box 149)
      - Greenbaum, Wolff & Ernst correspondence (Box 149)
      - Kay Collyer & Boose correspondence (Box 149)
      - Other correspondence, 2 (Box 149)
      - Doubleday correspondence, 9 (Box 150)
      - Doubleday royalty statements, 5 (Box 151)
      - Doubleday royalty statements, 3 (Box 152)
      - Viking Press correspondence (Box 152)
      - Viking royalty earnings (Box 152)
      - Other Publishers (Box 152)
      - Children of the Northlights movie (Box 152)
      - Lithographs for books (Box 152)
      - Reviews of D'Aulaire's work
        - Abraham Lincoln, 1939; 2 (Box 153)
        - Animals Everywhere, 1940, 1954; 3 folders (Box 153)
        - Benjamin Franklin, 1950 (Box 153)
        - Buffalo Bill, 1952 (Box 153)
        - Columbus, 1955; 2 (Box 153)
        - Don't Count Your Chicks, 1943 (Box 153)
        - Foxie, 1949-1950 (Box 154)
        - George Washington, 1938; 3 (Box 154)
        - Ingri and Edgar Parin D'Aulaire's Book of Greek Myths, 2 (Box 154)
        - Leif the Lucky, 1941, 1951; 2 folders (Box 154)
        - Leif the Lucky, 1941 (Box 155)
        - The Magic Meadow, 1958 (Box 155)
        - Nils, 1948 (Box 155)
        - The Two Cars, 1955 (Box 155)
        - Assorted reviews, 4 (Box 155)
        - Assorted reviews, 8 (Box 156)
        - Assorted reviews, 9 (Box 157)
      - Reviews and book catalogs, 6 (Box 158)
      - Reviews and book catalogs, 2 (Box 159)
      - Columbus, Ohio town meeting transcript, WBNS-TV, 1955 October 9 (Box 159)
        General note
        Edgar and Ingri Pain D'Aulaire were guest speakers for this event.
    - Personal Papers
      - Early correspondence, 4 (Box 160)
      - Unsorted correspondence, 2 (Box 160)
      - Correspondence, etc., 3 (Box 160)
        Includes unsorted correspondence, clippings, invitations, writings, and a notebook
      - Personal correspondence, 3 (Box 161)
      - Family photographs, 4 (Box 161)
      - Letters to and from Norway during the German occupation of World War II, 4 folders (Box 161)
      - Correspondence and other papers (Box 162)
      - Printed ephemera (Box 162)
      - Passports, 2 folders (Box 162)
      - Correspondence, etc., 2 (Box 163)
        Includes unsorted correspondence, postcards, writings, and printed material.
      - Personal correspondence and photographs, 3 (Box 163)
      - Old writings, printed material (Box 163)
      - Writings (Box 163)
      - Photographs, clippings, etc. (Box 163)
      - Theft, 1974-1978 (Box 163)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 163)
    - Photographs
      - Norway, 2 folders (Box 164)
      - New York (early years in America) (Box 164)
      - Wilton, Connecticut, 5 (Box 164)
      - Photographs of artwork (Box 164)
      - Vermont farmhouse, 3 (Box 164)
      - Greece, 4 folders (Box 164)
      - Passport photographs (Box 164)
      - "Special" photos (Box 164)
      - Portraits (Box 164)
      - Photographs used for books, 2 (Box 164)
      - Photographs used for books, 4 (Box 165)
      - Publicity photographs, 2 (Box 165)
      - Traveling and Paris (Box 165)
      - Book signings and Regina medal (Box 165)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 165)
      - Negatives, 5 folders (Box 165)
      - Negatives, 4 folders (Box 166)
    - Other Files
      - Clippings and ephemera, 5 (Box 167)
      - Revista de America, 1959 (Box 167)
      - Handmade cards to the D'Aulaires, 2 (Box 167)
      - Handmade book (Box 167)
      - Short Stories, 2 folders (Box 168)
      - Collections (Box 168)
      - Reprints (Box 168)
      - Photographs, 2 folders (Box 168)
      - Other publications, 2 (Box 168)
      - Articles, speeches, 2 (Box 168)
      - Art catalogs and exhibitions (Box 169)
      - Garbage dump (Box 169)
      - Garden (Box 169)
      - House plans, 2 folders (Box 169)
      - House renting (Box 169)
      - Promotion reviews (Box 169)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 169)
  - Objects
    - Caldecott medal (Box 170)
    - Wood blocks: donkey with cart, unknown image, 2 (Box 170)
    - Art supplies, 2 folders (Box 170)